

Thiago C.L. Silveira

POSTDOCTORAL FELLOW IN ECOLOGY-UFSO

Florianópolis, Santa Catarina-BR

□+55 48 99113 5385 | Silveira.tcl@gmail.com

About me

Graduated in Biological Sciences, Master's in Animal Biology (UFRGS) and Ph.D in Zoology (PUCRS - Sandwich Doctorate in Walles-UK). I currently work as a post-doc felow in Ecology on Post Graduation Program in Ecology (UFSC). I have experience in aquatic ecology whith emphasis in invertebrates, fishes, spatial models, and niche models. Also, I developed throughout my career programing skills using the **R software** in my research field, which enhanced my scientific thinking and influenced the way I teach in my lectures. My teaching experience is in postgraduation level, ranging from statistics and ecological practices in field ecology.

Skills & Interests

My background is in biological sciences, with enphasis in zoology and ecology. As a post-doc fellow I was encouraged to teach along five years and this experience gave me selfconfidence in class. The English idiom is part of my routine as a post-doc fellow, mainly for scientific reading and writing. My english speaking skills improved in 2019 when I was one of the lectures in a course entirely taught in English at UFSC. I consider myself fluent in English in most situations, also believe there is always room for improvement. I believe I can contribute and grow professionally at EIF.

Selected Teaching Experience

UFSC	Florianópolis-SC
ECOLOGY LECTURES (TAUGHT IN ENGLISH)	2019-2019
UFSC	Florianópolis-SC
SPECIES DISTRIBUTIONS AND NICHE MODELLING (TAUGHT IN PORTUGUESE)	2016-2018
UFSC	Florianópolis-SC
STATISTICS APPLIED TO ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYSIS (TAUGHT IN PORTUGUESE)	2016-2019
UFSC	Florianópolis-SC
Introduction to Multivariate Analisys (taught in Portuguese)	2016-2019
UFSC	Florianópolis
FIELD ECOLOGY (TAUGHT IN PORTUGUESE)	2016-2019

Education

PUCRS	Porto Alegre, RS
Ciências Biológicas	1999-2004
UFRGS	Porto Alegre, RS
Mestrado em Biologia Animal	2005-2007
PUCRS	Porto Alegre, RS
Doutorado em Zoologia	2011-2015



Skill	Portuguese	English	Spanish
Reading	Native	C1	B1
Writing	Native	B1	A2
Listening	Native	C1	B1
Speaking	Native	B2	A2

CEFR: A1/A2: Basic User. B1/B2: Independent User. C1/C2: Proficient User/ TOEFL-IBT 88 pts (2014)/ Spanish Proficiency Test - PUCRS (2013)

Technical Skills_____

Programing

R LANGUAGE

Software

QGIS - RSTUDIO - INKSCAPE - MENDELEY

Other

MARKDOWN - QUICKTIME - MOODLE

Additional Information _____

To access my complete CV, please go to my Lattes CV on http://lattes.cnpq.br/5960267776845701. If you want a personal reference, please get in touch with Dra. Andrea Santarosa Freire (freireandreas@gmail.com), coordinator of the Post Graduation Program in Ecology - UFSC.